

Website: http://kolev.io

Email: p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/plamen-kolev

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

ABOUT

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and web application deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies to build better software. I have worked with Perl, Bash, python for web development, PHP and ruby. I am a strong advocate for Linux and love working with open-source software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on high-performing, cyber security projects. Created automated tests using bash, Perl and in-house tools. Developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment in a large, multi-national team.

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions

April 2014 - June 2015

Conducted national studies across Britain on socio-political issues

Graphic Designer, Ivesto Company

September 2012 - June 2013

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University

September 2013 - Present

Studied object-oriented programing - design & development. relational database technologies. Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer Architectures. Software Engineering - principles and life cycle, scalability and maintenance.

Team projects, working as part of a group.

Distributed systems and modelling concurrent systems.

PROJECTS

Web Platform for Digital Deployment of Virtual Servers

November 2016 - Present

Currently creating a platform for deployment, management and monitoring of virtual servers as part of final year dissertation.

Technologies used: Puppet, BASH shell, Virtualbox, Vagrant, Ruby, Ruby On Rails.

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a PHP website for the Neven brand, the website is deployed here. It features internationalisation and stripe payment integration.

Secure Coding Presentation

5 May 2016

Gave a presentation in Lester College about different ways code can be exploited by a malicious user and ways to mitigate and avoid such cases.

Lloyds Banking

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the British bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team project.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU. Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

PAConsulting

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and control.